ABUL HASNAT MD. SAZEDUR RAHMAN

Chemical/Process Engineer

Address: Flat-6A, House-21, Road-18, Sector-11, Uttara, Dhaka.

(+880) 1715 686678

sazedurrahmanshohan@gmail.com, shohan@sazedurrahman.com



CAREER OBJECTIVE

A total of 5 years working experience in Multinational Organizations. Working as Production Officer-1 in Berger Paints Bangladesh Ltd., Former Sr. Executive of Health, Safety and Environment in LafargeHolcim Bangladesh Ltd., Passed in Chemical Engineering from BUET. Want to enrich my career with diversified roles and gained knowledge to hold a position of pinnacle importance.

SKILLS

Microsoft Office skills, Hard Worker and Working well under Pressure, Analytical skills, Computer skills, Problem-solving skills, Quick Learner, Critical thinking skills

EXPERIENCE

Berger Paints Bangladesh Ltd., Nobinogor, Savar, Dhaka - Production Officer-1

NOVEMBER 2017 - PRESENT

- Ensure regular production operation maintaining environment, health and safety of workers as well as machinery, equipment and process.
- Production planning and checking availability of raw materials in line with monthly production target.
- Manpower planning and ensuring optimum manpower utilization.
- Production reporting with productivity analysis and taking measures to improve productivity and reduce loss percentage.
- Calibration and inspection of required equipment including Kettle, mixing tanks, blender, storage tanks, Cooling Tower etc for production periodically.

LafargeHolcim Bangladesh Ltd., Chhatak, Sunamgonj - Senior Executive, HSE

JANUARY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Implementation of BS OHSAS 18001-2007, ISO 14001:2015 and ISO 90001:2015.
- Assisting and Training Plant team to perform Risk Assessment (HIRA), Work Permits (PTW),
 Life Saving Talks (LST) and other required tools and monitoring they are in place for all routine and non-routine work.
- Assisting plant team to find the root cause analysis after potential incidents and accidents.
- Performing HSE routine monitoring, data collection and assisting to prepare periodic reports for submission to govt and other required authorities.

• Supporting plant team being and active member of Safety Committee as required by Labor Law and working as Assistant Management Representative for External Audits.

ASM Chemical Industry, Sreepur, Gazipur - Management Trainee

SEPTEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

- Distribution Control System operation
- Production reporting

EDUCATION

$\textbf{Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET), Dhaka} \ - \textit{BSc in Chemical}$

Engineering

MARCH 2009 - AUGUST 2014

CGPA 3.45 out of 4.00.

Govt. Shaheed Bulbul College, Pabna - HSc in Science

MARCH 2006 - MAY 2008

CGPA 5.00 out of 5.00.

Govt. Shaheed Bulbul College, Pabna - SSc in Science

JANUARY 1996 - MAY 2006

CGPA 5.00 out of 5.00.

CERTIFICATION

Certified on Lead Auditor Training Course on OHSAS 18001:2007.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Traveling, Search Engine Optimization and Digital Marketing, Video Editing and Making Product Videos and some other software related works.